RG 069:019, James Bradford Olcott Papers
Connecticut State Library
James Bradford Olcott papers
1849-1938
Connecticut State Library
Olcott, James Bradford
7.25 cubic feet
James Bradford Olcott (1830-1910) was a horticulturist and writer from Manchester, Conn. Correspondence, diaries, photographs, plat books of the Manchester Turf Garden, file of agricultural articles from the Hartford Courant by Olcott, letters from a trip around Cape Horn and life in Sacramento, California.
RG069_019
1938-001
Biographical Note
Luther James Bradford Olcott was born on May 30, 1830 in Manchester, Connecticut to Sidney and Edna Adams Olcott. At the age of 16 Olcott was employed by the printing office of "The Republican" in Hartford Connecticut. He continued to work here until the age of 19 when in 1849 he followed the Gold Rush out to California. On his way to California Olcott traveled via the Henry Lee, a ship that sailed around Cape Horn. Olcott had little participation in the Gold Rush itself while in California. Instead, he chartered boats to foreign locations such as Tahiti to bring back exotic and foreign produce for profitable sale in America. During his time in Sacramento, California Olcott started a restaurant and boarding house.
In the early 1850s however, Olcott returned to Connecticut at the request of his mother. Upon his return, Olcott attended the Center Academy in Harwinton, Connecticut. Olcott worked on his father's farm for several years after leaving school. On October 20, 1856 he was married to Emiline A. Roberts, daughter of Isaac and Annie Ensign Roberts, of East Hartford Connecticut. After moving several times, the Olcotts finally ended up back in South Manchester, around 1865. Here Olcott worked for the Cheney Brothers who placed him in charge of all of their outdoor work, such as landscaping and building roads. In 1868, Olcott started his own farm in South Manchester which he would turn over to his son in 1890. Starting no later than 1869, Olcott wrote an agriculture column for the Hartford Courant, which touched on a wide variety of subjects including farming, road building, and growing grass. In 1880, Olcott sat on the committee whose job it was to investigate the proposal of land and money put forward by Augustus and Charles Storrs to develop an agricultural school in Storrs, Connecticut which would later become the University of Connecticut. In 1881 the proposal was accepted and the Storrs Agricultural School was developed, and James Bradford Olcott was invited to sit on its Board of Trustees.
In 1890, Olcott received a request from the Connecticut State Agricultural Experiment Station to begin collecting grasses that would be beneficial to Connecticut. That year Olcott began to develop his Turf Garden, which was located on just over an acre of land and contained various grasses laid out in 5 square foot "plats". Most of the tools used by Olcott in the cultivation of his Turf Garden he had invented himself. Through his work with grasses and the State Agricultural Experiment Station, Olcott was able to travel to places such as England, France, Germany, Denmark, and Australia as well as all over the United States. The purpose of these trips was to gain a better understanding of the cultivation of grasses as well as their natural climates. Just before his death Olcott had discovered which grasses were best suited for Connecticut's climate and had begun to set aside a large portion of his Turf Garden for the cultivation of this grass for seeding. In 1910, after having been restricted to a lawn chair for a year due to his failing health, James Bradford Olcott died of heart failure. He was survived by three of his children: Walter Hooker Olcott, Harry Ensign Olcott, and Annie Ensign Olcott Faulknor.
Sources:
1. Former finding aid.
2. "Manchester's Grass Authority Passes", 1910. Box 4, Folder 12.
3. Archives & Special Collections Staff. "James B. Olcott Papers." Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center: University of Connecticut..
4. "State's Grass Expert is Dead", 1910. Box 4, Folder 12.
Scope and Content
Series 1, California, 1849-1853, contains an account book detailing money received and debts owed during James Bradford Olcott's time in California between the years of 1849-1853. The series also contains correspondence written from the ship the Henry Lee which Olcott traveled on in transit to California during 1849. Other correspondence from his time in California, include letters to and from his family during the years of 1849 and 1851. Finally manuscript written by Olcott later in life, titled "Peach Pudding for Three Hundred Fifty" recounting several events from the time he spent in California as a young man.
Series 2, Correspondence, 1852-1906, contains letters from the colleagues of Olcott including Dr. William H. Brewer of Yale. Other colleagues also include the director of the Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station, from 1900 to 1923, Dr. Edward H. Jenkins. The bulk of Olcott's correspondence, however, comes from Dr. Jenkins' predecessor Dr. Samuel W. Johnson, director of the Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station during the years from 1877 until 1899. Other correspondences are more general while still mainly pertaining to his work with grasses as well as his work for the Hartford Courant.
Series 3, Manchester Turf Garden, 1890-1910, are detailed records of the various aspects of Olcott's care of his turf garden. The Manchester Turf Garden Records, despite going through several name changes, are journals recording the daily goings on from 1890 to 1910 in the Turf Garden. Also included in this series is a booklet containing lists of the grasses and where Olcott received them from. Finally, Olcott's Plat Lists contain information on where each grass is located within Olcott's Turf Garden for each year from 1890 up until 1893.
Series 4, Writings, 1869-1895, consists of speeches that Olcott had written for delivery as well as more general writings on his Horticulture work. More notably this series contains the book, "State Board of Agriculture Papers" which contains reports to the State Board of Agriculture from 1869 to 1890 mostly written by Olcott. A proposal, for Olcott's travel for the purpose of gaining more information about grasses in their originating countries, known as "The Argument" written to Director Johnson is included with a letter to Director Johnson. Also included are the articles Olcott wrote for the Hartford Courant, during the years between 1869 and 1889.
Series 5, Photographs, 1878-1937, fall into various subseries important to Olcott's life, however the main bulk pertains to his Turf Garden in one way or another. Portraits contain portraits of Olcott as well as one of his wife Mrs. Emily Roberts Olcott. Turf Samples contains photographs, as the title suggests, of turf samples taken from his Turf Garden. The subseries titled Turf Garden documents various work being done within Olcott's Turf Garden in South Manchester. Garden Tools displays the various tools Olcott used to maintain his Turf Garden several of which he had invented himself. The Ranch consists of photographs of Olcott's home which he had named "The Ranch".
Series 6, Newspaper clippings, 1881-1938, consists of newspaper clippings presumably taken by Olcott himself between the years of 1881 and 1906. Other clippings contained within this series, from 1914 to 1938, however may have been taken by his surviving family members after his death. Also contained here are Olcott's obituaries from his death in 1910 as well as a memorial piece from 1927 by the Manchester Evening Herald.
Related Material
Additional materials on James B. Olcott can be found in the located in the Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center of the University of Connecticut.
Index Terms
Persons:
Olcott, James Bradford; Brewer, William Henry, 1828-1910; Johnson, Samuel W. (Samuel William), 1830-1909
Places:
Manchester (Conn.); Sacramento (Calif.)
Subjects:
Horticulture -- Connecticut; Gold rushes--California--1850-1860; Turfgrasses -- Connecticut; Voyages to the Pacific
Document Types:
Correspondence; Photographs; Clippings; Notebooks; Speeches
Restrictions on Access
See the policy.
Provenance
This collection was given to the Connecticut State Library by James Bradford Olcott’s daughter Annie Ensign Olcott Faulknor in 1938.
Container List
- Series 1. California, 1849-1853, undated
  - Account book, 1849-1853 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Henry Lee (ship), 1849 February-April (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1849-1851, undated (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - "Peach-Pudding for Three Hundred Fifty", undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Series 2. Correspondence, 1852-1906, undated
  - William H. Brewer, 1884-1902 (Box 1, Folder 6-14)
  - Miss. Gilman, 1891-1896, undated (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
  - Edward H. Jenkins, 1884-1902 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Samuel W. Johnson (Box 1)
    - 1888-1890 (Box 1, Folder 18-21)
    - 1890-1896 June (Box 2, Folder 1-17)
    - 1896 June- 1898, undated (Box 3, Folder 1-10)
  - General correspondence (Box 3)
    - 1852-1897 June (Box 3, Folder 11-19)
    - 1897 September - 1906, undated (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
- Series 3. Manchester Turf Garden, 1890-1910
  All volumes are labled with an item number from a previous arrangement.
  - Manchester Turf Garden Records (Box 5)
    In some cases multiple volumes are bound together. Volumes 1 through 3 are titled "Record of the Manchester Grass-Garden", Volume 4 is titled "Record of Manchester Sward-Garden", Volumes 5 through 13 are titled "Record of the Manchester Turf-Garden", and Volumes 14 through 19 are titled "Record of the Connecticut Turf-Garden".
    - Volumes 1-2, 1890-1892; 1 volume (Box 5)
      Includes Volume 1A, Grass-List of the Manchester Grass-Garden
    - Volumes 3-4, 1892-1894; 1 volume (Box 5)
    - Volumes 5-6, 1894-1896; 1 volume (Box 5)
    - Volumes 7-8, 1896-1898; 1 volume (Box 5)
    - Volumes 9-10, 1898-1900; 1 volume (Box 6)
    - Volumes 11-12, 1900-1903; 1 volume (Box 6)
    - Volumes 13-14, 1903-1905; 1 volume (Box 6)
    - Volume 15, 1905-1906; 1 volume (Box 6)
    - Volume 16, 1906-1907; 1 volume (Box 6)
    - Volume 17, 1907-1908; 1 volume (Box 6)
    - Volume 18, 1908-1909; 1 volume (Box 6)
    - Volume 19, 1909-1910; 1 volume (Box 6)
  - List of grasses, 1890-1892 (Box 7)
  - Plat-Lists, 1890-1903 (Box 7)
    - Volume 15, Handy plat lists, 1890-1899; 1 volume (Box 7)
    - Volume 16, Scratch plat lists, 1898-1903; 1 volume (Box 7)
- Series 4. Writings, 1869-1895, undated
  - "State Board of Agriculture Papers" with annotations, 1869-1890 (Box 7)
  - Speeches, 1889, undated (Box 4, Folder 5-7)
  - "The Argument" with letter to Director S.W. Johnson, 1894-1895 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - General writings, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - J.B. Olcott's Agriculture Column for the Hartford Courant
    - January 2, 1869 - March 7, 1878 (Box 8)
    - March 14, 1878 - April 4, 1889 (Box 9)
- Series 5. Photographs, 1878-1937, undated
  - Portraits
    - Unidentified family with 12 adults and 4 children, undated; b&w, 3.75 x 5.5 in. (Box 12, Folder 87)
    - James Bradford Olcott, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 12, Folder 93)
    - Emily Roberts Olcott, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 12, Folder 94)
      Wife of James Bradford Olcott.
      From the portrait by Harriet Cheney.
    - James B. Olcott, 1893; b&w, 7.5 x 5.5 in., 21 copies (Box 12, Folder 101)
      "Supplement to Manchester Saturday Herald, July 29, 1893."
  - Turf Samples
    - Thirty labeled grass samples, undated; 4 photographs, b&w, 4.75 x 3 in. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Numbered samples (Box 10)
      - 1: Unidentified, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - 3: Unidentified, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - 5: Unidentified, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - 6: Unidentified, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - 7: Blue grass, Conway on the sea, Wales, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - 8: Unidentified, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - 11: Unidentified, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - 13: Unidentified, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - 14: Unidentified, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - 15: Unidentified, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - 16: Sweet vernal grass, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - 17: Unidentified, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - 18: Unidentified, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - 19: Unidentified, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - 20: Unidentified, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - 21: Unidentified, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - 23: Unidentified, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - 24: Festuca hatchett, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - 25: Festuca old dish, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - 26: Unidentified, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - 31: Unidentified, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - 32: Korai shiba, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - 34: Unidentified, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - 36: The edge of the grass garden, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - 37: Unidentified, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - 38: Unidentified, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - 42: Unidentified, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - 45: Unidentified, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - 46: Unidentified, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - "One once of seed per acre. The cheapest turf-grass seed in this market. Twenty-five hundred dollars per bushel.", undated; b&w, 4.5 x 6.5 in. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Agrostis plugged into festuca and shamrock, undated; b&w, 4.75 x 7 in., 4 photographs (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Agrostis plugged into festuca and shamrock, undated; b&w, 4.75 x 6.75 in., 4 photographs (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Poa plugged into festuca and shamrock, undated; b&w, 4.75 x 6.75 in., 2 photographs (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Festuca plugged into poa, undated; b&w, 4.75 x 6.75 in., (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Agrostis plugged into festuca, undated; b&w, 4.75 x 6.75 in., 2 photographs (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Agrostis plugged into poa, undated; b&w, 4.75 x 6.75 in., 3 photographs (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Agrostis and festuca two years old, undated; b&w, 4.75 x 6.75 in., 2 copies (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Plants cut out for square rod in April-July, undated; b&w, 4.75 x 6.75 in., 2 copies (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Unidentified grass sample, undated; b&w, 6.5 x 4 in. (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Unidentified grass sample, undated; b&w, 6.5 x 4 in. (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Unidentified grass sample, undated; b&w, 6.5 x 4 in. (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Unidentified grass sample, undated; b&w, 6.5 x 4 in. (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Grasses by location, undated; double-sided, b&w, 5.75 x 7.75 in. (Box 10, Folder 21)
      First side: "Baltimore Md.; Ottawa, Canada; Fort Hill, S.C.; Baltimore, Md.; N.C. & Baltimore; U.S. Dept. of Agri."
      Second side: "U.S. Dept of Agriculture; Richmond, Virginia; Georgia; Mississippi; Richmond, Va.; Phila., Pa."
    - Grasses by location, undated; double=sided, b&w, 5.75 x 7.75 in. (Box 10, Folder 22)
      First side: "Cousin Foster's back door; Mississippi Experiment Station; Pa----, Dedham, Ma., Cheever; Los B-----, 512, Stockton St., San Fran.; San Francisco, California; Dr. Mohr, Mobile."
      Second side: "Duplicate of the other side".
    - Grasses by location, undated; double-sided, b&w, 5.75 x 7.75 in. (Box 10, Folder 23)
      First side: "Richmond, Va.; Baltimore, Md.; Birmingham, Alabama; Baltimore, Md."
      Second side: "Georgia; Altanta, Geo.; U.S. Dept. of Agri.; A Exarata, Miss. Expt. Station".
    - "Seedman's Medley", "Seedman's Medley Rectified"; undated; double-sided, b&w, 5.75 x 7.75 in. (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - "Korai shiba, Yokohama", "Corea, Eragrostis ferruginea"; undated; double-sided, b&w, 5.75 x 7.75 in. (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - "Buffalo grass", "'232' spears to the square inch"; undated; double-sided, b&w, 5.75 x 7.75 in. (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - "Mouse-ear chickweed", "Perhaps useful chick weed"; undated; double-sided, b&w, 5.75 x 7.75 in. (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - "Brunella, a bad one", "The early blue aster"; undated; double-sided, b&w, 5.75 x 7.75 in. (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - "A. ordoratum just planted", "'A. ordoratum a week after planting"; undated; double-sided, b&w, 5.75 x 7.75 in. (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - "Turf for Connecticut 'Downs'", "Phalaris arundinacea moron"; undated; double-sided, b&w, 5.75 x 7.75 in. (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Grasses by location, undated; double-sided, b&w, 5.75 x 7.75 in. (Box 10, Folder 31)
      First side: "San Fran., Calif.; North Carolina Expt. Station; San Rafael, Calif.; E.W. Hitchcock, Cheyenne, Wyoming; Gov. Stanford, Palo Alto; Miss. Expt. Stat.; Fair View Sann Rafael."
      Second side: unidentified.
    - "Agrostis - Central Park - 6 weeks planted; ", "Two samples of Agrostis - 6 weeks planted - in comparison."; undated; double-sided, b&w, 5.75 x 7.75 in. (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - "A Good Find - Aug '93; ", unidentified; undated; double-sided, b&w, 5.75 x 7.75 in. (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - "Orchard-Grass from different places; ", "Dactylis from different places."; undated; double-sided, b&w, 5.75 x 7.75 in. (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - "Ireland - Fota; ", "Ireland - Kildate."; undated; double-sided, b&w, 5.75 x 7.75 in. (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - "Bouteloua, Salt grass of the plains, Bouteloua; ", "The results - Aug. '95."; undated; double-sided, b&w, 5.75 x 7.75 in. (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - "Cynodon dactylon - from all over the world; ", "Agrostis - Central Park, Smith - New Haven, N.C.F. Special."; undated; double-sided, b&w, 5.75 x 7.75 in. (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - "Zurich - Sr. Stebbins seed-control-station; ", "England - Beeston Castle."; undated; double-sided, b&w, 5.75 x 7.75 in. (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - "Sixteen in the family. Fesuca; ", "Day Asylum St. Htfd, Day Asylum St. Htfd. Old cherry pasture."; undated; double-sided, b&w, 5.75 x 7.75 in. (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - "As near to Botany as we get; ", "As near to Botany as we get."; undated; double-sided, b&w, 5.75 x 7.75 in. (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - "Reading, England; ", "North Wales - Conway - Salt. "; undated; double-sided, b&w, 5.75 x 7.75 in. (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Unidentified grass sample, undated; b&w, 8.5 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Unidentified grass sample, undated; b&w, 8.5 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Unidentified grass sample, undated; b&w, 8.5 x 5 in. (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Unidentified grass sample, undated; b&w, 8.5 x 5 in. (Box 10, Envelope 45)
  - Turf Garden
    - "The Square" still thriving in 1937, b&w, 5.5 x 4 in. (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - The "Turf Square". The Product of a single seed of festuca., undated; b&w, 4 x 5.5 in. (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - Olcott and another man working in the turf garden., undated; b&w, 4 x 5.5 in. (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - Turf garden with several segments empty of grass, 1907 December 31; b&w, 3.5 x 5.5 in. (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - Olcutts Grass Farm, South Manchester, Conn., undated; postcard, b&w, 3.5 x 5.5 in. (Box 11, Folder 50)
    - Turf garden with tracks through it, undated; b&w, 6.75 x 4.75 in. (Box 11, Folder 53)
    - Grass with leaves on the ground, undated; postcard, b&w, 6.75 x 4.75 in. (Box 11, Folder 54)
    - Views of the turf garden, undated; 2 leaves (4 photographs), b&w, 4.5 x 6.75 in. (Box 11, Folder 55)
      Side one: Turf garden with a man standing in the distance.
      Side two: Turf garden with clear deinition between grasses and a man standing in the distance.
      Side three: "The Turf-Garden of the Connecticut Experimental Station, Nov. 1896 [Published by the Connecticut Board of Agriculture].
      Side four: Chart of "Typeical breeds of sheep". Map depicting travel routes through Europe.
    - Views of the turf garden, undated; 2 leaves (4 photographs), b&w, 4.5 x 6.75 in. (Box 11, Folder 56)
      Side one: "Conn. Turf Garden, June 1st 1903."
      Side two: Turf garden with tracks through it.
      Side three: Olcutt in the turf garden with a woman in the background.
      "Conn. Turf Garden. Sat. May 16, 1903." Large ditch through the turf garden.
    - Olcott mowing the turf garden, undated; b&w, 3.5 x 6.75 in. (Box 11, Folder 57)
      Inscription on photograph: The turf-grass student.
    - Turf garden with visible squares, undated; b&w, 4.75 x 7 in. (Box 11, Folder 58)
    - The turf garden, undated; 2 photographs, b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 11, Folder 59)
    - Olcott with an umbrella in the turf garden, undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 11, Folder 60)
    - Olcott with an umbrella in the turf garden with woman in background., undated; b&w, 7 x 5 in. (Box 11, Folder 61)
    - Shed behind a tree at the edge of the turf garden, undated; 2 copies, b&w, 5 x 7 in. (Box 11, Folder 62)
    - Olcott working at "the Square". Several examples of tools are shown., undated; b&w, 4.75 x 6.75 in. (Box 11, Folder 63)
    - Olcott working in the turf garden., undated; 2 copies, b&w, 4.75 x 6.75 in. (Box 11, Folder 64)
    - Turf garden, undated; b&w, 4.75 x 6.75 in. (Box 11, Folder 65)
      Staining on photograph.
    - Album, undated; 12 photographs, b&w, 7 x 4.75 in. (Box 11, Folder 74)
      Subjects include: the turf garden; sheep.
    - Man working in station forage garden, undated; b&w, 5.25 x 8 in. (Box 11, Folder 75)
      Inscription on back: Station forage garden - by order of Dr. Johnson. No one who lived at the station knew how to use it. J.B.O. Lawn grass garden. Grass crawls in the midst.
    - "General view - Oct. 15th 1895; ", "Foreign collections six weeks planted.; undated; double-sided, b&w, 5.75 x 7.75 in. (Box 11, Folder 76)
    - "Assorting the seedsman's medley before replanting; ", "Foreign collection just planted. Aug. '95.; undated; double-sided, b&w, 5.75 x 7.75 in. (Box 11, Folder 77)
    - "Row 6. Larger area of one grass; ", "F. No. 1 Larger area of one grass."; undated; double-sided, b&w, 5.75 x 7.75 in. (Box 11, Folder 78)
    - Four girls working in the turf garden, undated; b&w, 4.75 x 6.25 in., mounted on cardboard 8 x 10 in. (Box 11, Folder 82)
      Inscription on photograph: The chick weeds.
    - Shed at the edge of the turf garden, undated; b&w, 4.75 x 6.25 in., mounted on cardboard 8 x 10 in. (Box 11, Folder 83)
      Inscription on photograph: Plank headquarters.
    - Man in turf garden with group of people at the edge, undated; b&w, 4.75 x 6.25 in., mounted on cardboard 8 x 10 in. (Box 11, Folder 84)
      Inscription on photograph: Keep off the grass.
    - Turf garden with man working in the distance, undated; b&w, 6.75 x 9 in., mounted in cardboard 8 x 10 in. (Box 11, Folder 85)
    - The turf garden of the Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station, Aug. 18, 1894, from the annual report of Connecticut Board of Agriculture for 1896, 1897; b&w, 12 x 50 in., image 7 x 46 in. (Box 12)
      "This engraving is from photographs now (March 1897) nearly three years old."
      Text surrounds the image.
      Item is rolled and is torn at both ends.
      There are two copies on tissue paper. These copies are folded and in fragile condition.
  - Garden Tools
    - Grass boxes that allowed for the continued growth of grass, even in winter, undated; b&w, 4 x 5.5 in. (Box 11, Folder 51)
    - Boxes allowing continued experimentation during the winter, undated; b&w, 3.25 x 5.5 in. (Box 11, Folder 52)
    - Assortment of garden tools, undated; b&w, 6.5 x 4.25 in. (Box 11, Folder 66)
    - Assortment of garden tools, undated; b&w, 6.5 x 4.25 in. (Box 11, Folder 67)